[{"question":"1.The most common circumstance for project closure is simply a ________ project.\nA.Completed\nB.Overdue\nC.Overbudget\nD.Under achiveing","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"The most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"2.What is not a wrap-up closure activity?\nA.Facilities\nB.Vendors\nC.Customer\nD.Profit report\nE.Report","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"See Figure 14.1 on page 505.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"3.__________ of lessons learned are designed to improve performance on current and future projects.\nA.Retrospectives\nB.Corrective action plans\nC.Introspective\nD.Culmination","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"Retrospectives of lessons learned are designed to improve performance on current and future projects.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"4.The content of the final report typically includes the following topics:\nA.Lessons learned\nB.Review and analysis\nC.Recommendations\nD.Executive summary\nE.All the above are correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"recommendations, lessons learned, and appendix.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"5.When the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated this is considered to be ___________closure.\nA.Normal\nB.Premature\nC.Perpetual\nD.Changed Priority","type":"fill-in","answer":"B.","help":"For a few projects, the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated. For example,in a new-product development project, a marketing manager may insist on production models before testing.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"6.This type of closure occurs when the project may never seem to end. This is considered to be ___________ closure.\nA.Normal\nB.Premature\nC.Perpetual\nD.Changed Priority","type":"fill-in","answer":"C.","help":"Some projects never seem to end. The major characteristic of this kind of project is constant \"add-ons,\" suggestinga poorly conceived project scope. At some point the review group should recommend methods for bringing finalclosure to this type of project or the initiation of another project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"7.Many projects will fail because of circumstances beyond the control of the project team is called:\nA.Normal\nB.Premature\nC.Perpetual\nD.Failed Project\nE.Changed Priority","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Failed projects are usually easy to identify and easy for a review group to close down, However, every effortshould be made to communicate the technical (or other) reasons for termination of the project; in any eventproject participants should not be left with an embarrassing stigma of working on a project that failed.Many projects will fail because of circumstances beyond the control of the project team.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"8.When a project may start with a high priority but see its rank erode or crash during its project life cycle asconditions change this is an example of:\nA.Normal\nB.Premature\nC.Perpetual\nD.Failed Project\nE.Changed Priority","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Organizations' priorities often change and strategy shifts directions. For example, during the 2008-10 financialcrisis organizations shifted their focus from money making projects to cost savings projects. The oversightgroup continually revises project selection priorities to reflect changes in organizational direction. Projectsin process may need to be altered or canceled. Thus, a project may start with a high priority but see itsrank erode or crash during its project life cycle as conditions change. When priorities change, projectsin process may need to be altered or canceled.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"9.Implementing closedown includes the following major activities except:\nA.Getting delivery acceptance from the customer.\nB.Shutting down resources and releasing to new uses.\nC.Closing accounts and seeing all bills are paid.\nD.E-mail the project team that the project is complete.\nE.Creating a final report.","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"See list on page 508","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"10.Which is not part of the team portion of the Wrap-up closure checklist?\nA.Has a schedule for reducing project staff been developed and accepted?\nB.Has staff been offered outplacement services and career counseling activities?\nC.Have performance reviews for team members been conducted?\nD.Has staff been released or notified of new assignments?\nE.All are included.","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"See Table 14.1 on page 508.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"11.Under which heading of the Wrap-up closure checklist should the question \"Has an in-depth project review andevaluation interview with the customer been conducted?\" be answered.\nA.Team\nB.Vendors/contractors\nC.Customer/Users\nD.Equipment and facilities\nE.Profit and loss statement","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"See Table 14.1 on page 508.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"12.Under which heading of the Wrap-up closure checklist should the question \"Have project accounts been finalizedand all billing closed?\" be answered.\nA.Team\nB.Vendors/contractors\nC.Customer/Users\nD.Equipment and facilities\nE.Profit and loss statement","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"See Table 14.1 on page 508.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"13.Releasing the project team typically occurs _________ during the closure phase.\nA.Gradually\nB.Rarely\nC.Without bombast\nD.Rapidly","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"Releasing the project team typically occurs gradually during the closure phase. For many people, terminationof their responsible activities ends before the project is delivered to the customer or user.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"14.In the Snapshot from Practice, New Balls Goes Flat in NBA, is an example of a project gone wrong when the _______is/are not consulted.\nA.Manufacture\nB.Equipment and facilities managers\nC.End-users\nD.Project manager","type":"fill-in","answer":"C.","help":"The failure to check with the players (the end-users) and get buy-in for the new basketball was loudly criticizedby the press. \"How they could actually even get it that far and not have run it by the players is just anamazing, amazing exercise in ineptitude.\"","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"15.Closing out _________ is often messy and filled with untied ends.\nA.Project review meetings\nB.Reports\nC.Invoices\nD.Teams","type":"fill-in","answer":"E.","help":"Since many work invoices are not submitted until after the project is officially over, closing out contractsis often messy and filled with untied ends.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"16.Information on the project type, size, number of staff, and technology level would be included in which sectionof the audit report?\nA.Analysis\nB.Recommendations\nC.Classification of project\nD.Lessons learned\nE.Strategic objectives","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"See list on page 524.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"17.Project mission and objectives, procedures and systems used, and organization resources used typically appearin the _____ section of the final project report.\nA.Analysis\nB.Recommendations\nC.Classification of project\nD.Lessons learned","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"The analysis section includes succinct, factual review statements of the projectâ€”for example, project missionand objectives, procedures and systems used, and organizational resources used.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"18.Items technical in nature and focus on solutions to problems that surfaced would typically appear in the _____section of the final project report.\nA.Analysis\nB.Recommendations\nC.Classification of project\nD.Lessons learned","type":"fill-in","answer":"B.","help":"Usually, review recommendations represent major improvement actions that should take place. They are often technicalin nature and focus on solutions to problems that surfaced.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"19.The section of the final project report that new project teams are likely to find most useful is the:\nA.Analysis\nB.Recommendations\nC.Classification of project\nD.Lessons learned\nE.Strategic objectives","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"In practice, new project teams studying past project reports similar to the project they are about to start havefound past review reports very useful.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"20.Corrective actions that should take place (such as shifting to more resilient building material) would typicallyappear in the _____ section of the final project report.\nA.Analysis\nB.Recommendations\nC.Classification of project\nD.Lessons learned","type":"fill-in","answer":"B.","help":"For example, to avoid rework, the report for a construction project recommended shifting to more resilient buildingmaterial. In other cases, they may include terminating or sustaining vendor or contractor relationships.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"21.In the Snapshot from Practice, the results of analyzing the Katrina hurricane resulted in a new evaluation planfrom:\nA.The state legislature\nB.The governor of Louisiana\nC.The city of New Orleans\nD.The Red Cross\nE.The national guard","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Lessons learned from Katrina disaster are not limited to the military. Almost every agency and support group,such as individuals, communities, churches, and other groups, has developed lessons learned from their projectresponse experience. For example, the Red Cross and state guard have better plans for handling thousandsof people problems involving shelter, evacuation, and medical assistance.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"22.The most common circumstance for project closure is:\nA.Premature completion with some features eliminated\nB.Project completion meeting costs, schedule, and quality\nC.Project completion after modification of costs, schedule, or quality\nD.Project termination due to technical difficulties\nE.Perpetual projects that seem to go on and on before completion","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project. For many development projects,the end involves handing off the final design to production and the creation of a new product or serviceline. Some modifications in scope, cost, and schedule probably occurred during implementation.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"23.Project closures can fall into all of the following categories except:\nA.Premature\nB.Perpetual\nC.Failed\nD.Changed priority\nE.All of these are categories for project closure","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"See list on Pages 506-507","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"24.In the Research Highlight, Chaos: Software Projects, the criterion which was deemed the most important for projectsuccess was\nA.Realistic expectations\nB.Hard-working, focused staff\nC.User involvement\nD.Proper planning\nE.Clear vision and objectives","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"The success criteria were weighted based on the input from the surveyed IT managers. The most important criterion,\"user involvement,\" was given 19 success points, while the least important, \"hard-working, focused staff,\"was given 3 success points.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"25.____________ begins with a review of the strategic intent of the project, selection criteria, project charter,project objectives, project scope, and acceptance criteria.\nA.Process Review\nB.Project Overview\nC.Analysis\nD.Recommendations","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"Process review begins with a review of the strategic intent of the project, selection criteria, project charter,project objectives, project scope, and acceptance criteria.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"26.The typical mechanism for evaluation of teams is normally:\nA.A survey completed by the team members\nB.A personal interview of each team member\nC.An analysis by an outside consultant\nD.A survey completed by members of top management\nE.A survey completed by the internal or external customers","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"With survey information in hand, the facilitator then visits one-on-one with project team members, the projectmanager, and other stakeholders to dive deeper into cause-effect impacts. Fundamentally, the attempt is toisolate \"the lack of x resulted in y.\"","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"27.More and more companies are discarding the traditional superior-subordinate performance feedback process andreplacing it with:\nA.Critical incidences review\nB.Management by objectives\nC.The 360-degree feedback\nD.Both B and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"More and more companies are discarding the traditional superior-subordinate performance feedback process andreplacing it with 360-degree feedback systems. The 360-degree feedback approach gathers behavioral observationsfrom many sources within the organization and includes employee self assessment.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"28.The project closure process includes all of the following except:\nA.Shutting down resources and releasing to new uses\nB.Reassigning project team members\nC.Conduct an audit\nD.Getting delivery acceptance from the customer\nE.Closing accounts and seeing all bills are paid","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Releasing the project team typically occurs gradually during the closure phase. For many people, terminationof their responsible activities ends before the project is delivered to the customer or user. Reassignmentfor these participants needs to take place well before the final finish date. In addition, for the remainingteam members (full or part time), termination may result in a new project or returning to their functionaljob. Also reassignment for these participants needs to take place well before the final finish date. Sincemany work invoices are not submitted until after the project is officially over, closing out contracts isoften messy and filled with untied ends. Finally getting delivery acceptance by the customer is a major andcritical closure activity.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"29.In organizations where projects are managed within a ____________, the team member's area manager, not the projectmanager, is responsible for assessing performance.\nA.Functional organization\nB.Matrix organization\nC.Flat organization\nD.Both A and C are correct","type":"fill-in","answer":"A.","help":"In organizations where projects are managed within a functional organization, the team member's area manager,not the project manager, is responsible for assessing performance.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"30.Performance evaluations of project teams should:\nA.Provide the basis for individual development\nB.Provide the basis for participation on future projects\nC.Provide the basis for salary increases\nD.Both A and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"action plans for improving performance. The second is evaluative and involves assessing how well the personhas performed in order to determine salary or merit adjustments.Fill in the Blank Questions","difficulty":"Fill in the Blank Questions"},{"question":"31.________ is the most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Normal","help":"Normal is the most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"32.The project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated is known as _________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"premature","help":"Premature for a few projects, the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"33.____________ are usually easy to identify and easy for a review group to close down.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Failed project","help":"Failed projects are usually easy to identify and easy for a review group to close down, however, every effortshould be made to communicate the technical (or other) reasons for termination of the project; in any eventproject participants should not be left with an embarrassing stigma of working on a project that failed.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"34.Projects in process may need to be altered or canceled. Thus, a project may start with a high priority but seeits rank erode or crash during its project life cycle as conditions change. This is called __________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"changed priority","help":"The oversight group continually revises project selection priorities to reflect changes in organizational direction.Projects in process may need to be altered or canceled. Thus, a project may start with a high priority butsee its rank erode or crash during its project life cycle as conditions change. When priorities change, projectsin process may need to be altered or canceled.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"35.A schedule for reducing project staff been developed and accepted is a question that is asked in the completionof the ___________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"wrap-up closure checklist","help":"See Table 14.1 on page 508.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"36.The summary simply highlights the key findings and facts relating to the project implementation is called the___________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"executive summary","help":"Executive Summary is the summary that simply highlights the key findings and facts relating to the project implementation.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"37.Some organizations have project closure checklists of over _____ wrap-up tasks!","type":"fill-in","answer":"100","help":"Some organizations have project closure checklists of over 100 wrap-up tasks!","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"38.The ________ section of the final project report includes succinct, factual review statements of the projectsuch as, project mission and objectives, procedures and systems used, and organizational resources used.","type":"fill-in","answer":"analysis","help":"The analysis section includes succinct, factual review statements of the projectâ€”for example, project missionand objectives, procedures and systems used, and organizational resources used.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"39.Perhaps _________ are the most valuable contribution of the closure process.","type":"fill-in","answer":"lessons learned","help":"Perhaps lessons learned are the most valuable contribution of the closure process.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"40.The ________ section of the final project report are often technical in nature and focus on solutions to problemsthat surfaced.","type":"fill-in","answer":"recommendations","help":"Recommendations are often technical in nature and focus on solutions to problems that surfaced.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"41.A completed ___________ is a good example of the need to work out the details in advance.","type":"fill-in","answer":"software program","help":"A completed software program is a good example of the need to work out the details in advance.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"42.A project closure is considered ________ if it never seems to end due to constant \"add-ons\" in attempt to improvethe project outcome.","type":"fill-in","answer":"perpetual","help":"Some projects never seem to end. The major characteristic of this kind of project is constant \"add-ons,\" suggestinga poorly conceived project scope.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"43.The purpose of ____________ is to assess how well the project team, team members, and project manager performed.","type":"fill-in","answer":"performance evaluation","help":"The purpose of project evaluation is to assess how well the project team, team members, and project manager performed.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"44.The ________ feedback approach gathers anonymous feedback solicited from others is compared with the individual'sself-evaluations, the individual may form a more realistic picture of her strengths and weaknesses.","type":"fill-in","answer":"360-degree","help":"When anonymous feedback solicited from others is compared with the individual's self-evaluations, the individualmay form a more realistic picture of her strengths and weaknesses.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"45.In some ____________, project managers conduct the performance reviews, while area managers are responsible forpay reviews.","type":"fill-in","answer":"matrix organizations","help":"In some matrix organizations, project managers conduct the performance reviews, while area managers are responsiblefor pay reviews.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"46.Project managers should be ________ giving team members feedback throughout the project so that individual teammembers can have a pretty good idea how well they have performed and how the manager feels before the formalmeeting.","type":"fill-in","answer":"constantly","help":"Project managers should be constantly giving team members feedback throughout the project so that individualteam members can have a pretty good idea how well they have performed and how the manager feels before theformal meeting.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"47.The _________ of projects by characteristics allows prospective readers, teams, and project managers to be selectivein the search and use of report content.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Classification","help":"The classification of projects by characteristics allows prospective readers, teams, and project managers tobe selective in the search and use of report content.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"48.The most common reason given for not creating lessons learned is _________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"lack of time","help":"The most common reason given for not creating lessons learned is lack of time.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"49.A ________ is a methodology that analyzes a past project event to determine what worked and what didn't, developslessons learned, and creates an action plan that ensures lessons learned are used to improve management offuture projects.","type":"fill-in","answer":"retrospective","help":"A retrospective is a methodology that analyzes a past project event to determine what worked and what didn't,develops lessons learned, and creates an action plan that ensures lessons learned are used to improve managementof future projects.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"50._________ are binary; either you have reached requirements completion or you have not.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Milestones","help":"Milestones are binary; either you have reached requirements completion or you have not.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"51.The Standish Group International's market research on software projects, called Chaos showed that ___ percentof all software projects are cancelled before completion.31","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"31","help":"The Standish Group International is a market research and advisory firm specializing in mission critical softwareand electronic commerce. They have conducted and published extensive research on the success and failureof software development/application projects. Their research, code name \"Chaos,\" shows that a staggering31 percent of software projects will be canceled before they are ever completed.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"52.A __________ is a guide who leads the project team through an analysis of project activities that went well,what needs improvement, and development of a follow-up action plan with goals and accountability.","type":"fill-in","answer":"project facilitator","help":"A project facilitator is a guide who leads the project team through an analysis of project activities that wentwell, what needs improvement, and development of a follow-up action plan with goals and accountability.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"53.__________ represent an analysis carried out during and shortly after the project life cycle; they attempt tocapture positive and negative project learning.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Lessons learned","help":"Lessons learned represent an analysis carried out during and shortly after the project life cycle; they attemptto capture positive and negative project learning.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"54.An upbeat, festive celebration brings closure to the enjoyable experiences everyone has had and the need to saygood-bye is considered to be a ____________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"celebration","help":"A final wrap up activity for the facilitator is the project closure celebration. An upbeat, festive celebrationbrings closure to the enjoyable experiences everyone has had and the need to say good-bye. Celebration isan opportunity to recognize the effort project stakeholders contributed.True / False Questions","difficulty":"True / False Questions"},{"question":"55.In a Perpetual project the most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Normal project is where the most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"56.In a Premature projects, the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Premature for a few projects, the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"57.Retrospectives of lessons learned are designed to improve performance on current and future projects.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Retrospectives of lessons learned are designed to improve performance on current and future projects.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"58.When a project may start with a high priority but see its rank erode or crash during its project life cycle asconditions change this is an example of change changed priority.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Organizations' priorities often change and strategy shifts directions. For example, during the 2008-10 financialcrisis organizations shifted their focus from money making projects to cost savings projects. The oversightgroup continually revises project selection priorities to reflect changes in organizational direction. Projectsin process may need to be altered or canceled. Thus, a project may start with a high priority but see itsrank erode or crash during its project life cycle as conditions change. When priorities change, projectsin process may need to be altered or canceled.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"59.Part of the content of the final report typically includes profit made on the project.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"recommendations, lessons learned, and appendix.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"60.The project manager's challenge is to keep the project team focused on the remaining project activities and deliveryto the customer until the project is complete.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The project manager's challenge is to keep the project team focused on the remaining project activities and deliveryto the customer until the project is complete.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"61.Implementing closedown includes getting delivery acceptance from the customer.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"See List on page 508.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"62.Project Summary is the summary that simply highlights the key findings and facts relating to the project implementation.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Executive Summary is the summary that simply highlights the key findings and facts relating to the project implementation.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"63.Analysis examines in detail the underlying causes of problems, issues, and successes.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Analysis examines in detail the underlying causes of problems, issues, and successes.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"64.The ideal scenario is to have the team member's next assignment ready when project completion is announced.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The ideal scenario is to have the team member's next assignment ready when project completion is announced.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"65.The maximum items on a checklist for closing a project are 50.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Closing out a project can be intimidating. Some organizations have checklists of over 100 wrap-up tasks!","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"66.Lessons learned from the Katrina disaster are not limited to the military. Almost every agency and support group,such as individuals, communities, churches, and other groups, has developed lessons learned from their projectresponse experience.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Lessons learned from the Katrina disaster are not limited to the military. Almost every agency and support group,such as individuals, communities, churches, and other groups, has developed lessons learned from their projectresponse experience.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"67.Evaluation of individuals implies measurement against all team members.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Evaluation implies measurement against specific criteria.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"68.Performance evaluations of project team members are typically well done because the evaluations are conductedby the team member's home department.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"In a macro sense, the evidence today suggests that performance evaluation is not done well. The major reasonsmember's home department. 2. Typical measures of team performance center on time, cost, and specifications.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"69.The most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project such as building a new facilityor creating a customized information system.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Normal is the most common circumstance for project closure is simply a completed project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"70.A project closure where the project is completed early with some parts of the project eliminated would be classifiedas project failure.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"For a few projects, the project may be completed early with some parts of the project eliminated. For example,in a new-product development project, a marketing manager may insist on production models before testing.This is a premature closing project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"71.The key requirement in selection of the facilitator is one who is the end-user.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The key requirement in selection of the facilitator is independence.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"72.Performance appraisals generally fulfill five important functions.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"is on identifying individual strengths and weaknesses and developing action plans for improving performance.The second is evaluative and involves assessing how well the person has performed in order to determine salaryor merit adjustments.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"73.Some organizations rely simply on an informal discussion between the project manager and the project member whileother organizations require project managers to submit written evaluations that describe and assess an individual'sperformance on a project.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Some organizations rely simply on an informal discussion between the project manager and the project member whileother organizations require project managers to submit written evaluations that describe and assess an individual'sperformance on a project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"74.A 360-degree performance evaluation includes feedback from peers, project managers, subordinates, and even customers.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"One process that appears to be gaining wider acceptance is the multirater appraisal or \"360-degree feedback,\"which involves soliciting feedback concerning team members' performance from all the people their work affects.This would include not only project and area managers, but also peers, subordinates, and even customers.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"75.Project managers should, when possible, draw comparisons to other team members when conducting individual teammember reviews.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Avoid, when possible, drawing comparisons with other team members; rather, assess the individual in terms ofestablished standards and expectations. Comparisons tend to undermine cohesion and divert attention awayfrom what the individual needs to do to improve performance.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"76.Retrospective methodology is one positive step toward ensuring lessons learned are developed and implemented.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Retrospective methodology is one positive step toward ensuring lessons learned are developed and implemented.Short Answer Questions","difficulty":"Short Answer Questions"},{"question":"77.What are the six major activities implementing project closedown?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Getting delivery acceptance from the customer, 2. Shutting down resources and releasing to new uses, 3. Reassigningproject team members, 4. Closing accounts and seeing all bills are paid, 5. Delivering the project to thecustomer, 6. Creating a final report.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"78.Identify the four areas of the project closure checklist.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Team, 2. Vendors/contactors, 3. Customers/users, 4. Equipment and facilities.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"79.Identify the three major deliverables for project closure.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Wrapping up the project, 2. Evaluation of performance and management of the project.3. Retrospectives.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"80.How does the project managers meet the challenge to keep the project team focused on the remaining project activitiesand delivery to the customer until the project is complete?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Communicating a closure and review plan and schedule early allows the project team to (1) accept the psychologicalfact the project will end and (2) prepare to move on. The ideal scenario is to have the team member's nextassignment ready when project completion is announced. Project managers need to be careful to maintain theirenthusiasm for completing the project and hold people accountable to deadlines, which are prone to slip duringthe waning stages of the project.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"81.Identify the five common parts to the final project report.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Executive Summary, 2. analysis of information gathered, 3. recommendations, 4. lessons learned, and 5. appendix.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"82.Identify and briefly describe the five most common classifications for the way that projects end.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. normal; project ended as planned, 2. premature; project ended early with some parts eliminated, 3. perpetual;project extend due to increases in scope, 4. failed; project could not be completed, and 5. changed priority;shifts in organization priorities due to changes in market or technology.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"83.List the five, distinguishing characteristics to ensure Retrospectives methodology embedded effectiveness andvalue?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Uses an independent facilitator. 2. Includes a minimum of three in-process learning gates during the lifeproject cycle. 3. Has an owner. 4. Develops a repository that is easy to use. 5. Mandates a discipline thatensures retrospectives are used.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"84.How does Norman Kerth define retrospective in his text Project Retrospectives?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"A retrospective is a methodology that analyzes a past project event to determine what worked and what didn't,develops lessons learned, and creates an action plan that ensures lessons learned are used to improve managementof future projects.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"85.What guidelines should a project manager follow in conducting performance reviews?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Have the individual prepare a self-evaluation, 2. compare with standards not other people, 3. focus on specificbehaviors rather than the individual, 4. be consistent and fair with all team members, and 5. treat the reviewas a point in an ongoing process.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"86.What is a 360-degree feedback and how is it used?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"A 360-degree feedback is a performance evaluation technique that is gaining popularity in project management.It solicits feedback from all the people that the team member's work affects, e.g., project managers, peers,subordinates and customers.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"87.In the Research Highlight \"Measures of Team Performance,\" what was the major finding of the research survey?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. too few teams (52%) received a collective evaluation of their performance and 2. of the 22% who said theydid receive an evaluation, it lasted only approximately 20 minutes.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"88.Explain what Lessons learned represent.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Lessons learned represent an analysis carried out during and shortly after the project life cycle; they attemptto capture positive and negative project learning. That is, \"what worked and what didn't?\" Lessons learned(postmortems, post-project review, or whatever name you choose to use) have long been part of project management.14-1","difficulty":"1"}]